# SAAD ARSHAD

- House No.145, Sapphire Block, Park View Villas, Main Multan Road Lahore, Pakistan
- \$\square\$ +92321-7044704
- saad.arshad@outlook.com, mian\_saadi23@yahoo.com



## **OBJECTIVE**

I am an experienced resource having "CAN-DO" attitude and more than o5 years' experience in the field of Human Resource Management. Looking for challenging opportunity where I can utilize my skills and perform fully for the company growth and self-motivation with a long term relationship of honesty and loyalty.

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- SAP HCM (Front End)
- Recruitment & Selection
- HR Policies & Procedures
- Employee Files Management
- Compensation & Benefits
- Payroll Management
- Attendance & Leave Management
- Performance Management
- Employee Insurance

#### CAREER EXPERIENCE

Total = 05 Years

## **Company** Atcon-The Construction Professionals

Duration : Aug, 2015 to Present

Position : Manager HR



# **About the Company**

Atcon provides comprehensive construction services. Atcon is known for having ability to deliver projects with exceptional quality on time and budget. Through the use of our extensive tools and plants and with the efforts of subcontractors, suppliers and our professional teams, atcon provide the necessary labour, materials, tools, equipment, temporary utilities and facilities to complete construction of a project.

### <u>Job Duties & Responsibilities:</u>

- Maintains organization staff by establishing a recruiting, testing, and interviewing program; counseling managers on candidate selection; conducting and analyzing exit interviews; recommending changes.
- Prepares employees for assignments by establishing and conducting orientation and training programs.
- Maintains the work structure by updating job requirements and job descriptions for all positions.
- Maintains a pay plan by conducting periodic pay surveys; scheduling and conducting job evaluations; preparing pay budgets; monitoring and scheduling individual pay actions; recommending, planning, and implementing pay structure revisions.
- Maintains management guidelines by preparing, updating, and recommending human resource policies and procedures.
- Maintains historical human resource records by designing a filing and retrieval system; keeping past and current records.
- Maintains human resource staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees.
- Maintains human resource staff job results by counseling and disciplining employees; planning, monitoring, and appraising job results.
- Contributes to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed.

# <u>Company</u> Banu Mukhtar Contracting (Pvt.) Limited

Duration : Oct, 2012 to July 2015

Position : HR Team Lead



# About the Company

Banu Mukhtar Contracting (Pvt.) Limited is the lead Company of Banu-Mukhtar - incorporated in 1964 and carrying around 5 decades of rich and dynamic expertise in Construction Management, Planning, Designing, Supervision and Execution. The Company has to its credit construction of scores of Industrial, Commercial, Institutional Buildings and High Rise Structures involving all kinds of Civil, MEP and HVAC works.

# <u>Job Duties & Responsibilities</u>

- Lead the SAP HCM Training. (Front End)
- Employee Recruitment and Selection.
- Manage all necessary arrangements before and after hiring.
- To facilitate the new employees throughout in their induction process.
- Compensation and payroll Management.
- Performance Management.
- Develop & Implement the HR Policies and Procedures.
- Managing the attendance management system.
- Responsible for Group takaful.

# <u>Company</u> Mechanics Engineering Services

Duration : Sep, 2010 to Sep, 2012

Position : HR Executive



## **About the Company**

"MECHANICS" Engineering Services have gained reputation in the market by dint of standard and specific services and supplies relating to Power and Generators Sets (Gas/Diesel) to the worthy Clients during the last 15 years. MECHANICS is a sign of 'Standard working' side by side fulfilling the satisfaction of the worthy clients with our services.

## <u>Job Duties & Responsibilities</u>

- Recruitment. (Reviewing resume and applications)
- Conducting first round of telephonic interview for the candidates to schedule interviews.
- Working with recruitment agencies to source for candidates for specific job positions.
- Maintaining HR records, such as those related to compensation, health and medical insurance.
- Managing workplace safety issues.
- Orientation and manage trainings new or existing employees.
- Firing staff: Conducting exit interviews from employee.
- Communicating and explaining the organization's HR policies to the employees.
- Recording, maintaining and monitoring attendance to ensure employee punctuality.
- Preparing letters such as offer, appointment, confirmation, transfer etc.
- To ensure the employees registration with EOBI, Social Security.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

- Master in Business Administration (Human Resource) By Securing 3.41 CGPA from Superior
  University Lahore affiliated with HEC, Pakistan in session 2013-2015.
- Bachelors in Commerce (Hons) By Securing 3.63 CGPA from Superior University Lahore affiliated with HEC, Pakistan in session 2009-2013.
- Intermediate in Commerce By Securing 62% Marks from Superior Group of Colleges affiliated with Punjab Board, Lahore, Pakistan in session 2007-2009.
- Matriculation By Securing 56% Marks from Govt. N.D Islamia High School affiliated with Lahore Board, Pakistan in 2007.

### **CERTIFICATE'S/TRAINING'S/SEMINAR'S**

- Trained Person of SAP HCM Module. (Front Desk)
- Certificate of Achievement in National Research Symposium 2014 by Superior University Lahore.
- Certificate of Presenting Research Paper in International Conference on Management
  Research 2014 at Superior University Lahore by IESEG School of Management, France.
- Certification of "Class Facilitator" during my education session.
  - Attended Max. Babri Training on "Leadership"
  - Attended Red Crescent Training on "Save life"
  - Attended Seminar on "Positive Thinking" by Prof. Usman Wali.
  - Attended Seminar on "Personality Development" by Mr. Javeid Ch.
  - Acquired training on Advance Excel and Dreamweaver Software in Superior University.
  - Acquired training on "Peachtree Accounting Software" in Superior University.
  - Attended a Seminar on 'Professional Grooming" by Prof. Mahwish Zafar.
  - Attended the Seminar on "Winning Attitude" by Prof. Akther Abbas Senior HR Consultant.

### LANGUAGES SKILLS

English, Urdu and Punjabi – (Reading, Writing & Speaking Skills)

# **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

- Building Public Relations.
- Researching in Human Psychology.
- Book Reading, Internet surfing, playing with systems & software's, Music.

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Father Name : Arshad Ali Sajid D.O.B : 23<sup>rd</sup> February, 1993

Nationality : Pakistani Marital Status : Single

NIC No : 35202-0609549-1

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.